Derek Mackley

Staff Product Security Engineer
Warrior, AL 32951 · (770) 402-6341
Derek.Mackley@hotmail.com
https://www.linkedin.com/in/DMackley
https://github.com/DapperDivers

SUMMARY

Disciplined and ambitious BSA Eagle Scout who sets and achieves goals. This correlates with my track record of releasing quality software on time, with teams of all sizes, and budgets. I've worked in a variety of industries with multiple tech stacks and am very passionate about Cybersecurity and lifelong learning.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Management Skills: Effectively take business requirements and then plan, schedule, and release quality software. Interviewing, hiring, and building effective teams. Strategic planning for business requirements balanced with technical debt, and modernization.
- Programming Proficiencies: .NET, C#,C++, SQL, MVC, Webforms, AngualarJS, Angular, React, NPM, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Visual Studio, Microsoft Azure, LINQ, Entity Framework, PHP, Laravel, Python, Flask, Mosquito MQTT, EMQX, Tera Term, Linux development, Ansible, Azure Devops, Git, Docker, Proxmox, AWS, Google Cloud, Azure, Kubernetes, Helm, NestJS, Reloader, ArgoCD, Trivy, Github Actions, ChatGPT, Gemini, Anthropic
- Certifications: Practical Network Penetration Tester (PNPT), AINS 21, Google Cybersecurity

EXPERIENCE

Mastery Logistics Systems

Remote

Staff Product Security Engineer

July 2023 - Present

- As a Staff Product Security Engineer and technical lead of a newly formed product security team, I established a comprehensive vulnerability management program for the organization. This included aggregating vulnerabilities from both proprietary and open-source tools, building Power BI dashboards to visualize risk, and developing documentation to guide remediation of critical findings. I demonstrated risk by actively enumerating and exploiting the most significant vulnerabilities in our test environment.
- To shift security left, I designed and implemented a suite of GitHub Actions that automatically scan every pull request for secrets, vulnerable packages, and outdated base images. This automation significantly reduced risk by catching issues early in the development lifecycle.
- Additionally, I developed a custom tool to map Kubernetes resources to GitHub repositories, enabling the association of security findings with specific teams and regions. This innovation allows for targeted scanning and, soon, automated creation of Jira tickets with SLAs to track and ensure timely remediation. These efforts have transformed how security findings are managed, prioritized, and resolved across the organization.
- LOTS of behind the scenes work on AI development. Lets have a conversation to see how I can help.

Senor Software Engineering Manager

May 2022 - July 2023

• Worked as the Senior Software Engineering Manager in the International region at Mastery Logistics Systems. In this role I led my teams to successfully complete projects including integrations with ITS, Slack, Teams, an IMDL aggregation tool, and a "flat-file" integration that's being used by multiple domains. While in this role I led as many as 9 teams and have helped to define the SDLC for the international region. This role required the ability to juggle many projects simultaneously as well as facilitate communication between many technical and non-technical team members. While in this role my responsibilities included very hands on technical work to resolve bugs or solve deployment issues, to large scale project planning with multiple teams.

Traction Tools Remote

Software Engineering Manager

February 2021 - May 2022

• Worked as the Software Engineering Manager for a direct-to-consumer site that provides tooling for businesses running EOS. I led the software, QA, and project management teams, overseeing sprint management, code reviews, tech stack, and the direction of the product from an engineering standpoint. While in this role I instituted Azure Devops, automated deployments, unit testing, integration testing, selenium tests and a two-week sprint/release cadence to the organization. I led the effort to modernize the tech stack, by methodically migrating the website from .NET 4.6.1 MVC Razor and AngularJS, to a microservices architecture with a react front end. This involved moving from AWS virtual machines to an ECS cluster, as well as migrating the current project to .NET Core while ensuring no downtime and adding new features. Basically, rebuilding the car piece by piece while in a drag race.

Satcom Direct (Contract)

Melbourne, Fl

Senior Software Engineer

July 2020 - February 2021

• Contract role working with a large array of microservices written in .Net C#. This includes some Azure functions as well as windows forms apps, MVC applications, .net API's, an Angular 7 portal, and many others. The purpose of all of this is to receive, manipulate, and enhance messages from planes and then send them back to the pilot in real time. Most of the development in this position was "high risk" as any mistakes made could force a plane to land. This creates the need for high coverage of unit and integration tests, with architecture planned around high availability.

Ubicquia Melbourne, Fl

Senior Software Engineer / Development Lead

February 2019 - June 2020

At this startup, I learned an incredible amount and overcame unique challenges on a day-to-day basis. This role involved creating an enterprise solution to manage cellular connected units on light poles. While in this role, I wrote and managed a PHP Laravel API, with an Angular front end, as well as wrote automation frameworks, MQTT broker connections, python API's, virtualized environments, and a whole host of supporting software. I also learned to manage and configure Linux environments and wrote Ansible scripts to migrate and re-architect the business from Azure to the Google Cloud Platform. The last one saving the company 500K annually. This role involved managing a small team (myself in the back-end, 2 people in the FE, and 1 in QA) with big tasks, and short deadlines. This taught me to move quickly, focus on what is truly important, and to write extensible software with manageable tech debt.

Medicomp Inc Melbourne, FI

Senior Software Developer / Development Lead

May 2018 - February 2019

• While at Medicomp I primarily worked on their direct-to-consumer website AAW that displays reports to doctors nationally. The site was written in webforms and Jquery the challenge being to implement new features and using standard best practices while supporting legacy code. This includes creating new features to use primarily web methods, as well as rewriting pieces of the application in order to facilitate a move to a more modern architecture. I managed a team of four to prioritize work and ensure quality. Before this project I was on a team that attempted to fix an outsourced MVC 5, knockout.js application hosted in Azure that analyzed and diagnosed patient's ECG data

Starr Companies Atlanta, GA

Application Developer & Global/IT Associate

March 2016 - May 2018

• At Starr Companies, I quickly transitioned from the Global Associates program, where I gained hands-on exposure to the Property and Casualty insurance industry by collaborating with industry leaders, to a key developer role supporting critical internal applications. I rapidly learned new technologies and business processes, contributing directly to the modernization of a Document Management and Reporting web portal. My work included migrating the platform from on-premise to Azure, transitioning from WebForms to MVC 5, and upgrading resource-heavy pages to Angular JS, all while expanding the user base from 30 to over 250 underwriters.

EDUCATION

Georgia State University, J. Mack Robinson College of Business

Atlanta, GA

Bachelor of Business Administration, Computer Information Systems

January 2015

Minor: Information Security

PERSONAL DEVELOPMENT

Homelab 2016 - Present

• High-availability Proxmox cluster utilizing Talos, Kubernetes, and GitOps for automated management; 180TB ZFS storage; secrets secured with SOPS.

https://github.com/DapperDivers/dapper-cluster

Random other Engineering

2020 - Present

- RFID / NFC happy to send you a business card :)
- Prototype esp based RFID car key hardware and software
- lots of 3D printers

Outside Stuff 2007 - Present

- PADI Divemaster
- Woodworking